Finding Aid for Nathan W. Shock Papers 1906-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Gerontology Research Center, 1940-1978
  - Baltimore Longitudinal Study Of Aging
    - 25th Anniversary, September 9-11, 1983; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Appointment schedules, 1983-1988 (Box 24)
    - Normal Human Aging, 1984 (Box 24)
    - Normal Human Aging, reviews and clippings, 1985 (Box 24)
    - New participants, 1985 (Box 24)
    - Published journal articles, 1985-1986 (Box 24)
    - Scientific American manuscript, 1986-1987 (Box 24)
    - 30th Anniversary, 1988 (Box 24)
  - Center for Aging Research
    - Activities, highlights, programs, 1955-1962; 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Conference on Aging, 1957-1958 (Box 24)
    - General file, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
    - General file, 1957-1958 (Box 25)
    - General file, 1959 (Box 25)
    - General file, 1960-1963 (Box 25)
    - Research trips, 1956-1959 (Box 25)
    - Aging centers
      - University of California, 1958 (Box 25)
      - Washington University, 1956 (Box 25)
      - Jacksonville and Gainesville, Florida, 1956 (Box 25)
      - Purdue University, 1957 (Box 25)
      - Fels Research Institute, 1957 (Box 25)
      - State University of Iowa, 1957 (Box 25)
      - Stanford University, 1960 (Box 25)
    - Training Needs in Psychosocial Gerontology, Conference, Palm Beach, Florida, 1956 (Box 25)
    - Federal Council on Aging, Report to the President, 1957 (Box 25)
    - Task Force on Aging, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Baltimore City Hospitals
    - Archives (Box 25)
    - Organization, 1946; 1952; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Gerontology Section relationship to Baltimore City Hospitals, 1947-1963 (Box 25)
    - Research grants, 1947-1953 (Box 25)
    - Remodeling of B-building for Gerontology Research Center, 1948-195?
      - General (Box 25)
      - Contract and grant, 1951 (Box 25)
    - Infirmary building committee, 1949 (Box 25)
    - Mental health project, 1950-1958 (Box 25)
    - McMillin, P.J., memoranda, 1952-1958 (Box 25)
    - Human performance study, 1952-1958; 2 folders
      - Reports, 1956-1957 (Box 25)
    - Nursing grant, 1954-1958 (Box 25)
    - Influenza study, 1957 (Box 26)
    - Ward B-2, 1958-1963 (Box 26)
    - BCH Record, 1959-1964 (Box 26)
    - Staff appointments, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Census records, 1965-1972 (Box 26)
    - Watt Report, 1956
      - Background, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Gerontology Research Center, Building Records
    - Historical records justifying the GRC building, 1957-1964; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Animal facilities, 1967-1976 (Box 26)
    - Building bids, 1965 (Box 26)
    - Building Committee, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Building Committee, Gerontology Patient Center, 1966-1968 (Box 26)
    - Building deficiencies, corrections, 1968-1970 (Box 26)
    - Cold rooms, 1964-1970 (Box 26)
    - Computer needs, 1967-1977 (Box 26)
    - Contract with Baltimore City Hospitals, 1963-1973 (Box 26)
    - Electron microscopy, 1973-1974 (Box 26)
    - Equipment, 1964-1968; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Equipment, laboratories, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Maryland State Commission on Aging, 1961-1967 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1976 (Box 26)
    - Nursing requirements, 1970-1973 (Box 26)
    - Occupancy, 1968 (Box 26)
    - Operating costs, policy, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Plans, 1967 (Box 27)
    - Plant operations, 1968-1970 (Box 27)
    - Policy Advisory Committee, 1963-1967 (Box 27)
    - Radioisotopes policy, undated (Box 27)
    - Space allocation, 1967 (Box 27)
    - Transport section, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Visiting scientists, 1961-1968 (Box 27)
  - National Institute On Aging
    - Background documents, 1958-1976 (Box 27)
    - Historical documents, 1969-1975 (Box 27)
    - Support of research on adult development and aging, reports, 1968-1974 (Box 27)
    - Executive staff, 1975 (Box 27)
    - Statement, National Institutes of Health Councils to President's Biomedical Research Panel, September 30, 1975 (Box 27)
    - Planning reports, 1975 (Box 27)
    - Panel report, research in health service systems, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Program analysis task force, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Executive staff, 1976 (Box 27)
    - National Advisory Council on Aging, 1977-1979; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Speech, Robert N. Butler, Director, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Board of Scientific Councilors, 1976 (Box 28)
    - Bibliographies, annual, 1983-1987 (Box 28)
    - 10th anniversary, 1985 (Box 28)
    - Geron-News, 1988 (Box 28)
- Conferences
  Conferences (2.5 linear feet) covers the period 1938 to 1981 and is arranged in chronological order; all deal with aging.
  - First Russian Conference on Senility, Kiev, December 17-19, 1938 (Box 28)
  - Conference on Aging, Federal Security Administration, Washington Final report, August 13-15, 1950 (Box 28)
  - Conference on Aging, Federal Security Administration, Washington Papers, press releases, programs, August 13-15, 1950 (Box 28)
  - Conference on Aging, Federal Security Administration, Washington Planning and post-conference documents, August 13-15, 1950; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Conference on Aging, Federal Security Administration, Washington Proceedings, August 13-15, 1950 (Box 28)
  - Second Clinical ACTH Conference, Chicago, December 8-9, 1950 (Box 28)
  - Conference on Aging, American Institute for Research, Pittsburgh, May 30, 1952 (Box 28)
  - Federal-State Conference on Aging, Washington, June 5-7, 1956 (Box 28)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1956; 1957; 1958; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - National Advisory Health Council, Committee on Aging, May 21, 1959 (Box 28)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1959; 1960; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1961
    - Planning (Box 28)
    - Policy statements and recommendations (Box 28)
    - Program (Box 28)
    - Recommendations from the States (Box 28)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1961; 1962; 1963; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1964; 1965; 1966; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Adaptive Capacities of An Aging Organism, Kiev, USSR, June 6-9, 1967 (Box 29)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1967; 1968; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health, December 2-4, 1969 (Box 29)
  - Life Span Conference, Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Santa Barbara, April 13-17, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1970; 1971; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1971; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1972; 1973; 1974; 1975; 1976; 5 folders (Box 29)
  - Epidemiology of Aging, Conference, Bethesda, March 28-29, 1977 (Box 29)
  - National Council on the Aging, 27th Annual Conference, April 19, 1977 (Box 29)
  - Institute de la Vie, Aging, A Challenge to Science and Social Policy, Vichy (France), April 24-30, 1977
    - Planning (Box 29)
    - Program (Box 29)
    - Papers (Box 29)
  - Ohio Board of Regents, Columbus, January 14, 1978 (Box 30)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Agency, Steps Toward Space Technology, Ames Research Center, Moffett Field, California, January 30-31, 1978 (Box 30)
  - Life-course Perspectives on Middle and Old Age, Social Science Research Council, Stanford University, May 4-5, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Life, Heat and Altitude, Dill Symposium, University of Nevada, Las Vegas, May 15-17, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Conference on Mass Media and Aging, Columbia University, September 28, 1979 (Box 30)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1981 (Box 30)
- Foundations
  In the Foundations series (1.5 linear feet) the files pertaining to the Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation are of the most interest. The Macy Foundation is credited with fathering the study of aging through its sponsorship of The Club for Research on Aging (1940-1953), and for interesting the National Institutes of Health in beginning the aging research program within the federal government.
  - Josiah Macy, Jr., Foundation
    - Club for Research on Aging
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 30)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 30)
      - 1st meeting, Washington, D.C., January 12-13, 1940 (Box 30)
      - 2nd meeting, Baltimore, MD, March 21-22, 1941 (Box 30)
      - Conference on Nutritional Requirements for the Aging Population, Ithaca, N.Y., November 1-2, 1941 (Box 30)
      - 3rd meeting, Baltimore, February 28-March 1, 1942 (Box 30)
      - 4th meeting, New York, February 13-14, 1943 (Box 30)
      - 5th meeting, New York, February 5-6, 1944 (Box 30)
      - 7th meeting, New York, February 9-10, 1945 (Box 30)
      - 8th meeting, New York, February 18-19, 1946 (Box 30)
      - Meeting, New York, February 3-4, 1947 (Box 30)
      - Meeting, New York, February 9-10, 1948 (Box 30)
      - 11th meeting, New York, April 25-26, 1949 (Box 30)
    - Conference on Problems of Aging (continues the activities of the Club for Research on Aging)
      - 12th meeting, New York, February 6-7, 1950 (Box 30)
      - 13th meeting, New York, February 5-6, 1951 (Box 30)
      - 14th meeting, St. Louis, September 7-8, 1951 (Box 30)
      - 15th meeting, Princeton (final meeting), January 20-22, 1953 (Box 30)
      - Transactions, Conference on Problems of Aging, N.W. Shock, Editor (Box 30)
      - Assessment of Conference on Problems of Aging, N.W. Shock, 1969 (Box 30)
    - Conference on Renal Function, New York, October 20-21, 1949 (Box 30)
    - 2nd Conference on Renal Function, New York, October 19-20, 1950 (Box 30)
    - 3rd Conference on Renal Function, New York, October 18-19, 1951 (Box 30)
    - 4th Conference on Renal Function, New York, October 23-24, 1952 (Box 30)
    - 5th Conference on Renal Function, Princeton, October 14-16, 1953 (Box 30)
    - Twenty year review of the activities of the Josiah Macy, Jr., Foundation, draft report, 1950 (Box 30)
    - History of the Josiah Macy, Jr., Foundation's contribution to gerontology, 1953 (Box 30)
    - Foreign guests lists (Box 30)
  - Other Foundations
    - Orentreich Foundation for the Advancement of Science, 1965-1971 (Box 31)
    - The Longevity Foundation, 1960-1963 (Box 31)
    - Glenn Foundation for Medical Research, 1987 (Box 31)
- International Association of Gerontology
  The next series is that of the International Association of Gerontology (4 linear feet) covering the period from its founding in 1950 to 1989. Dr. Shock was president of the group from 1966 to 1969 and was in charge of its 8th International Congress, held in Washington, D.C. in August 1969. The records are most comprehensive for this period of the Association.
  - History, 5 folders
    - Manuscript preparation, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - President's Chain of Office (Box 31)
    - History outline (Box 31)
    - The International Association of Gerontology-A Chronicle from 1950-1986, By N.W. Shock, 1988 (Box 31)
  - By-laws and guiding principles, 1959-1963 (Box 31)
  - IAG Newsletter and Bulletin, 1964-1969 (Box 31)
  - 1st International Congress of Gerontology, Liege, Belgium, July 10-12, 1950 (Box 31)
  - 2nd International Congress of Gerontology, St. Louis, September 9-14, 1951; 3 folders (Box 31)
  - 3rd International Congress of Gerontology, London, July 19-23, 1954
    - Post-Congress Gerontological Study Tour (Box 31)
  - 4th International Congress of Gerontology, Merano, Italy, July 14-20, 1957 (Box 32)
  - 5th International Congress of Gerontology, San Francisco, August 7-12, 1960
    - Biological Research Committee, 1961 (Box 32)
    - Council meeting, 1960 (Box 32)
    - Council, 1963-1968 (Box 32)
  - 6th International Congress of Gerontology, Copenhagen, August 11-16, 1963; 2 folders
    - Torben Geill, President, correspondence, 1963-1966
      - Geill correspondence with American Geriatric Society, 1966 (Box 32)
      - Geill correspondence with Australia (Box 32)
      - Geill correspondence with F. Bourliere, 1963-1966 (Box 32)
      - Geill correspondence with W. Doberauer, 1963-1966 (Box 32)
      - Geill correspondence with Germany (DDR) and Czechoslovakia, 1965-1966 (Box 32)
      - Geill correspondence with South America, Spain, 1966 (Box 32)
  - 7th International Congress of Gerontology, Vienna, June 27-July 3, 1966; 4 folders (Box 32)
  - 8th International Congress of Gerontology, Washington (Nathan W. Shock, President), August 24-29, 1969
    - General, 3 folders (Box 32)
    - NIH grant (Box 32)
    - Other grants (Box 32)
    - Fund raising (Box 32)
    - Mailing lists (Box 32)
    - Student fellowships (Box 32)
    - Travel awards (Box 32)
    - IAG Council, 1966-1969 (Box 33)
    - Executive Committee meetings, 1965-1969 (Box 33)
    - Advisory Committee (Box 33)
    - Finance Committee
      - Budget, 1965-1968 (Box 33)
      - Budget, 1969-1972 (Box 33)
    - Sponsorships (Box 33)
    - Program Committee, 1966-1969 (Box 33)
    - Time schedules (Box 33)
    - Reports to Gerontological Society, American Geriatric Society (Box 33)
    - Colloquia, symposia, discussion sessions (Box 33)
    - Correspondence with W. Doberauer, 1966-1969 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence with H.B. Lemp, 1966-1969 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence with E.J. Lorenze, 1966-1969 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence with R.J. Van Zonneveld, 1966-1969 (Box 33)
    - Brochure (Box 33)
    - Films (Box 33)
    - Program name listings (Box 33)
    - Entertainment (Box 33)
    - Exhibits (Box 33)
    - United Nations resolution, December 1969 (Box 33)
    - Opening session remarks by President Nathan W. Shock (Box 33)
    - Post-Congress congratulations (Box 33)
    - Press and publicity (Box 33)
    - Publications (Box 33)
    - Tours (Box 33)
    - Translation services (Box 33)
    - Review of the Congress, in Gerontologist 10, no. 1, pt. 1, Spring 1970 (Box 33)
  - 9th International Congress of Gerontology, Kiev, July 2-7, 1972
    - Program (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, D. Chebotarev, President, 1969-1977; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, Israeli participation, 1971-1972 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1971-1973 (Box 33)
    - Council records, 1970-1975 (Box 33)
    - Executive Committee, 1970-1972
      - General (Box 33)
      - Meeting, Paris, April 1-3, 1971 (Box 34)
      - Meeting, Paris, November 17-20, 1971 (Box 34)
    - Finance Committee, 1970-1976 (Box 34)
    - Program planning, 1970-1972 (Box 34)
    - NIH grant (Box 34)
    - United States speakers (Box 34)
    - Announcements, 1970-1972 (Box 34)
    - Social sciences sessions (Box 34)
    - Governing body members, 1968-1973 (Box 34)
    - United Nations, 1971-1977 (Box 34)
  - 10th International Congress of Gerontology, Jerusalem, June 22-27, 1975
    - Planning (Box 34)
    - Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 34)
    - Program planning (Box 34)
    - Plenary speech, N.W. Shock (Box 34)
  - 11th International Congress of Gerontology, Tokyo, August 20-25, 1978
    - General (Box 34)
    - Council meetings (Box 34)
    - By-laws revision (Box 34)
    - Symposium, "Human longitudinal studies" (Box 34)
  - 12th International Congress of Gerontology, Hamburg, July 12-17, 1981 (Box 34)
  - 13th International Congress of Gerontology, N. Y., July 12-17, 1985
    - Finance Committee (Box 34)
    - General (Box 34)
    - Past Presidents' Symposium, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - 14th International Congress of Gerontology, Acapulco, June 19-23, 1989 (Box 34)
  - European Clinical Section
    - 4th Congress, Sanremo, Italy, September 1965 (Box 34)
    - 5th Congress, Brussels, September 1968 (Box 34)
  - Member Societies
    - Australia (Box 34)
    - Brazil (Box 35)
    - Canada (Box 35)
    - Hungary (Box 35)
    - Japan (Box 35)
    - Pakistan (Box 35)
    - Puerto Rico (Box 35)
    - Venezuela (Box 35)
- International Organizations - Other
  The series, International Organizations-Other, (0.5 linear feet) covers the period 1956-1982, and for the most part, represents those meetings in which Shock took part.
  - 1st Pan-American Congress of Gerontology, 1956 (Box 35)
  - New Zealand Committee on the Care of the Aged, 1960-1966 (Box 35)
  - International Research in Aging, London, May 3-5, 1965 (Box 35)
  - Australian Council on the Aging, newsletters, 1960-1969 (Box 35)
  - Exchange Visits in the Health Sciences with Rumania, 1969-1970 (Box 35)
  - European Biological Symposia, 3rd, 4th, 6th, 1970-1979 (Box 35)
  - National Congress of Gerontology, Mexico City, November 23-25, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Institut de la Vie, Vichy Conference "Indices of physiologic age", 1978 (Box 35)
  - International Organization for the Study of Human Development, 1978-1982 (Box 35)
  - International Federation on Aging, 1978-1979 (Box 35)
  - C.I.G.S. (International Center of Social Gerontology), 1971-1977 (Box 35)
  - C.I.G.S. (International Center of Social Gerontology), 1985-1986
    - Conference, Quebec, August 27-30, 1980 (Box 35)
    - Newsletter, 1973-1979 (Box 35)
  - World Assembly on the Aged, Vienna, 1982 (Box 35)
- Gerontological Society of America (GSA)
  The series, Gerontological Society of America(GSA) (5 linear feet), is a detailed record of the Society from its beginning in 1946 to 1988. Dr. Shock was an active participant in the work of the Society throughout his long career and there is much here that contributes to an understanding of the growth of the discipline of gerontology as well as the contribution the Society made to the field.
  - History (Box 35)
  - Relations with American Geriatric Society, 1950 (Box 35)
  - Affiliate groups, 1953-1958 (Box 35)
  - By-laws
    - 1946 (Box 35)
    - Revision, 1952 (Box 35)
    - Revisions, 1957-1984 (Box 35)
  - Certificate of incorporation, May 18, 1945 (Box 35)
  - Expansion proposal, 1951 (Box 35)
  - 1st Annual Meeting, New York, January 8-9, 1949 (Box 35)
  - 1st-10th Annual Meetings, Programs and Abstracts, 1949-1957 (Box 35)
  - Council Meetings
    - St. Louis, September 10, 1951 (Box 35)
    - Washington, September 6, 1952 (Box 35)
    - San Francisco, August 25, 1953 (Box 35)
    - Gainesville, December 29, 1954 (Box 36)
    - Baltimore, October 28, 1955 (Box 36)
    - Chicago, November 7, 1956 (Box 36)
    - Cleve, November 1, 1957 (Box 36)
    - Philadelphia, November 5, 1958; November 7, 1958 (Box 36)
  - 11th Annual Meeting, Philadelphia, November 6-8, 1958 (Box 36)
  - 12th Annual Meeting, Detroit, November 12-14, 1959
    - President N.W. Shock's correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, Detroit, November 11, 1959; November 13, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, San Francisco, August 6, 1960; August 9, 1960 (Box 36)
  - Annual Meeting, Pittsburgh, November 9-11, 1961
    - President J.T. Freeman's correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, 1961 (Box 36)
  - Federation with American Geriatrics Society, proposal, 1962 (Box 36)
  - Organization chart (Box 36)
  - Recommendation to White House Conference on Aging, 1960 (Box 36)
  - Curriculum Project, 1962-1964 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, Miami Beach, November 7, 1962; November 9, 1962 (Box 36)
  - 16th Annual Meeting, Boston, November 7-9, 1963 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, Boston, November 6, 1963; November 8, 1963 (Box 36)
  - 17th Annual Meeting, Minneapolis, October 29-31, 1964 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, Minneapolis, October 28, 1964; October 30, 1964 (Box 36)
  - 18th Annual Meeting, Los Angeles, November 11-13, 1965
    - Symposium, Current Issues in Gerontology (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, Los Angeles, November 10, 1965; November 12, 1965 (Box 36)
  - 19th Annual Meeting, New York, November 3-5, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, New York, November 2, 1966; November 4, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Projects, 1966-1968 (Box 36)
  - 20th Annual Meeting, St. Petersburg, November 9-11, 1967 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, St. Petersburg, November 8, 1967; November 10, 1967 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, Denver, October 30, 1968; November 1, 1968 (Box 36)
  - Council Meeting, Rolling Meadows, IL, January 29, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Washington, June 8, 1970 (Box 37)
  - Congressional testimony, 1970 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Washington, May 14-15, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Annual Meeting, Houston, October 27-30, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Houston, October 27, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, February 19, 1972 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, New York, April 4, 1972 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, San Juan, Puerto Rico, December 16, 1972; December 18, 1972 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Washington, June 15, 1973 (Box 37)
  - 26th Annual Meeting, Miami Beach, November 5-9, 1973 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Miami Beach, November 4, 1973 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Washington, June 7, 1974 (Box 37)
  - 27th Annual Meeting, Port, October 28-November 1, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Port, October 28, 1974; October 30, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Washington, June 6, 1975 (Box 37)
  - 28th Annual Meeting, Louisville, October 26-30, 1975 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, Louisville, October 26, 1975; October 28, 1975 (Box 37)
  - 29th Annual Meeting, New York, October 13-17, 1976 (Box 37)
  - Council Meeting, New York, October 13, 1976; October 14, 1976 (Box 37)
  - 30th Annual Meeting, San Francisco, November 18-21, 1977 (Box 37)
  - Council Meetings, 1977 (Box 37)
  - 31st Annual Meeting, Dallas, November 15-21, 1978 (Box 37)
  - 32nd Annual Meeting, Washington, November 25-29, 1979 (Box 37)
  - 33rd Annual Meeting, San Diego, November 21-25, 1980 (Box 37)
  - 34th Annual Meeting, Toronto, November 8-12, 1981 (Box 37)
  - 35th Annual Meeting, Boston, November 19-23, 1982 (Box 37)
  - 36th Annual Meeting, San Francisco, November 18-22, 1983 (Box 37)
  - 37th Annual Meeting, San Antonio, November 16-20, 1984 (Box 38)
  - 40th Annual Meeting, Washington, November 18-22, 1987 (Box 38)
  - Committees, general, 1958-1960 (Box 38)
  - Affiliate Organizations and Local Chapters Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 38)
  - Archival Material Collection Committee, Proposal for a history and archives of gerontology and geriatrics, 1975-1987 (Box 38)
  - Awards Committee, 1969-1974 (Box 38)
  - Biological Research Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 38)
  - Biological Sciences Section, 1961-1976 (Box 38)
  - Brookdale Award, 1979; 1980 (Box 38)
  - Brookdale Award, 1982 (Box 38)
  - Brookdale Award, 1983 (Box 38)
  - Brookdale Award, 1984 (Box 38)
  - Classified Bibliography of Gerontology and Geriatrics, Documentation Committee, 1961-1967; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Finance and Development Committee, 1956-1965 (Box 38)
  - Finance Committee, 1977 (Box 38)
  - Finance Committee, 1978 (Box 38)
  - Ford Foundation grant, 1958 (Box 38)
  - History of Gerontology Committee, 1960-1965
    - Oral History Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 38)
  - Local Arrangements Committee, 1954-1961 (Box 38)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 38)
  - Membership Committee, 1948-1975 (Box 38)
  - Newsletter Evaluation Committee, 1955-1960 (Box 38)
  - Nominations Committee, 1957-1965 (Box 38)
  - Policy and Planning Committee, 1960 (Box 38)
  - Presidential Advisory Group, 1960 (Box 38)
  - Procedural Guide Committee, 1961; 1964; 1968 (Box 38)
  - Professional Membership Committee, 1953-1957 (Box 38)
  - Program Committee, 1958-1964 (Box 38)
  - Public Relations Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 39)
  - Publications Committee
    - 1960-1967 (Box 39)
    - 1968 (Box 39)
    - 1969 (Box 39)
    - 1970 (Box 39)
    - 1971, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - 1972 (Box 39)
    - 1973, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - 1974 (Box 39)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 39)
    - 1986-1988 (Box 39)
    - Gerontological Society Newsletter, (incomplete), 1954-1976 (Box 39)
    - Gerontology News, (incomplete), 1981-1988 (Box 39)
    - Student Newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box 39)
    - The Gerontologist
      - 1960-1967 (Box 39)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 39)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 39)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 39)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 39)
    - Journal of Gerontology
      - 1949-1962 (Box 39)
      - 1963-1983 (Box 39)
  - Research and Fellowship Committee, 1957-1959 (Box 39)
  - Research Committee, 1960-1965 (Box 39)
  - Treasurer's report, 1959 (Box 39)
  - The Nathan Shock New Investigator Award, 1986-1988 (Box 40)